<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools on Chris Hager</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/tags/tools/</link><description>Recent content in Tools on Chris Hager</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.metachris.com/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TLS Certificate Cheat Sheet - OpenSSL &amp; Curl</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/2025/09/tls-certificate-cheat-sheet-openssl-curl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/2025/09/tls-certificate-cheat-sheet-openssl-curl/</guid><description>This is a cheat sheet for working with TLS certificates: generating keys, certs and CSRs, signing, validating and inspecting certificates, and testing TLS connections.
I&amp;rsquo;ve originally put these together for myself when working with TLS certs and ACME recently, and thought I would share them since they might be helpful to others. Let me know if you find it useful, and if you have suggestions for improvements!
About TLS Transport Layer Security (TLS) is a cryptographic protocol that provides secure communication over a computer network using public key cryptography and digital certificates to authenticate the communicating parties and to encrypt the data transmitted between them.</description></item><item><title>My Mac Dev Setup and Favorite Tools</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/2024/01/my-mac-dev-setup-and-favorite-tools/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/2024/01/my-mac-dev-setup-and-favorite-tools/</guid><description>How I setup and use my computer and tools for development.
I wrote this mostly as a guide for myself, for the next time I setup a computer, and hope it might be useful to others too. I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your thoughts, ideas and additional tips in the comments below!
Related: How I setup my Terminal and Bash.
Contents Mac setup Keyboard shortcuts Browser Terminal &amp;amp; Shell Docker for Node.</description></item><item><title>Terminal and Bash - Tips &amp; Tricks</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/2024/01/terminal-and-bash-tips-tricks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/2024/01/terminal-and-bash-tips-tricks/</guid><description>&lt;p>A collection of notes, tips and tricks about how I setup and use my terminal (iTerm2) and shell (Bash). Perhaps you find some of it useful or interesting for your own setup.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>