<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Server on Chris Hager</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/tags/server/</link><description>Recent content in Server on Chris Hager</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.metachris.com/tags/server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Free Transactional Email Services - The Best Alternatives to Mandrill &amp;amp; Co.</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/2016/03/free-transactional-email-services-the-best-alternatives-to-mandrill/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/2016/03/free-transactional-email-services-the-best-alternatives-to-mandrill/</guid><description>Mandrill, the beloved-by-many transactional email service, recently announced that it will switch to a paid-only model under the MailChimp umbrella. This came as a surprise to many developers who used them for sending emails for free from various servers and backends. This post provides a round-up of some of the more popular Mandrill alternatives.
Free Transactional Email Providers This section covers a number of popular transactional email providers with a free tier.</description></item><item><title>How to Optimize Wordpress Performance with nginx and WP Super Cache</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/2016/02/how-to-optimize-wordpress-performance-with-nginx-and-wp-super-cache/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/2016/02/how-to-optimize-wordpress-performance-with-nginx-and-wp-super-cache/</guid><description>This is a simple and effective method how to serve Wordpress pages blazingly fast: produce static HTML files with WP Super Cache, and serve them directly with nginx.
WP Super Cache (on Github) is an immensely popular, official Wordpress caching plugin with more than 1 million active installations. Basically the plugin produces static html pages of your posts and pages, and anonymous users can directly load the html without any interaction with PHP.</description></item><item><title>Comparison of 10 ACME / Let's Encrypt Clients</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/2015/12/comparison-of-10-acme-lets-encrypt-clients/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/2015/12/comparison-of-10-acme-lets-encrypt-clients/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt is a new certificate authority backed by Mozilla, Akamai, EFF, Facebook and others, which provides free, automated SSL/TLS certificates. The public beta started on December 3, 2015 and a whole lot of certificates have been issued already:
Several clients to automate issuing, renewing and revoking certificates have been released both by the community and the Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt team. This post is an overview and comparison of 10 popular Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt clients:</description></item></channel></rss>