<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PDFx on Chris Hager</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/tags/pdfx/</link><description>Recent content in PDFx on Chris Hager</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.metachris.com/tags/pdfx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PDFx update and new version release (v1.4.1)</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/2021/04/pdfx-update-and-new-version-release-v1.4.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/2021/04/pdfx-update-and-new-version-release-v1.4.1/</guid><description>&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/metachris/pdfx">PDFx&lt;/a> is a tool to extract text, links and metadata from PDF files and URLs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to &lt;a href="https://github.com/metachris/pdfx/graphs/contributors">several contributors&lt;/a> the project received a thorough update (and was brought into 2021) with the release of &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/pdfx/">PDFx v1.4.1&lt;/a> 🎉&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PDFx works like this:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Find broken hyperlinks in a PDF document with PDFx</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/2016/03/find-broken-hyperlinks-in-a-pdf-document-with-pdfx/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/2016/03/find-broken-hyperlinks-in-a-pdf-document-with-pdfx/</guid><description>PDFx is a free command-line tool to extract references, links and metadata from PDF files. You can also use it to find broken links in a PDF file, using pdfx -c:
For each URL and PDF reference, pdfx performs a HEAD request and checks the status code. It there are broken links, PDFx print the link with the page number where the link was found in the original pdf:
$ pdfx https://weakdh.</description></item><item><title>PDFx v1.0 - Extract metadata and URLs from PDFs, and download all referenced PDFs</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/2015/10/pdfx-extract-metadata-and-download-references-from-pdfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/2015/10/pdfx-extract-metadata-and-download-references-from-pdfs/</guid><description>I just released PDFx version 1.0, a Python tool and library to extract metadata and URLs from PDFs, and to automatically download all referenced PDFs. The project is released under the Apache license with the source code on Github!
Features Extract metadata and PDF URLs from a given PDF (file or URL) Download all PDFs referenced in the original PDF Works with local and online pdfs Use as command-line tool or Python package Compatible with Python 2 and 3 Quick Start Grab a copy of pdfx with easy_install or pip and run it:</description></item></channel></rss>