<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>How-To on Chris Hager</title><link>https://www.metachris.dev/tags/how-to/</link><description>Recent content in How-To on Chris Hager</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.metachris.dev/tags/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to install Qt 5.6 and PyQt5 in a Python 3.4 virtual environment on Mac OS X and Linux</title><link>https://www.metachris.dev/2016/03/how-to-install-qt56-pyqt5-virtualenv-python3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.dev/2016/03/how-to-install-qt56-pyqt5-virtualenv-python3/</guid><description>This is a simple guide on installing the latest Qt (currently 5.6) and PyQt5 on Mac OS X 10.11 (El Capitan) and Linux with Python 3.4, inside a virtual environment.
Installation Steps
Python 3 Xcode and command-line tools Qt libraries Virtual environment SIP Python package PyQt5 Python package Python 3 First of all, make sure that Python 3 is available on your system. You can easily check this by opening the terminal and entering the command python3.</description></item><item><title>How to Optimize Wordpress Performance with nginx and WP Super Cache</title><link>https://www.metachris.dev/2016/02/how-to-optimize-wordpress-performance-with-nginx-and-wp-super-cache/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.dev/2016/02/how-to-optimize-wordpress-performance-with-nginx-and-wp-super-cache/</guid><description>This is a simple and effective method how to serve Wordpress pages blazingly fast: produce static HTML files with WP Super Cache, and serve them directly with nginx.
WP Super Cache (on Github) is an immensely popular, official Wordpress caching plugin with more than 1 million active installations. Basically the plugin produces static html pages of your posts and pages, and anonymous users can directly load the html without any interaction with PHP.</description></item></channel></rss>