<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Chris Hager</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Chris Hager</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.metachris.com/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Most Simple Ajax Chat Ever</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/projects/most-simple-ajax-chat-ever/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/projects/most-simple-ajax-chat-ever/</guid><description>Most Simple Ajax Chat Ever
A fun little project from January 2006. Back then ajax just started becoming popular, but with very few tools around. jQuery came out later that year, Github just two years later, in 2008.
Original code on Github Original site on web.archive.org Featured on Wired in February 2006
Features
Super simple Efficient spam filter (thanks to some live &amp;lsquo;hackers&amp;rsquo; at launch) Only 2 files needed (index.</description></item><item><title>PDFx - Extract references and metadata from PDF documents, and download all referenced PDFs</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/pdfx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/pdfx/</guid><description>Reading over this paper and its references recently, I thought it would be great to be able to download all the references at once&amp;hellip; This inspired me to write a little tool to do just that, and now it&amp;rsquo;s done and released under the Apache open source license:
https://github.com/metachris/pdfx
Features
Extract references and metadata from a given PDF Detects pdf, url, arxiv and doi references Fast, parallel download of all referenced PDFs Find broken hyperlinks (using the -c flag) (more) Output as text or JSON (using the -j flag) Extract the PDF text (using the --text flag) Use as command-line tool or Python package Compatible with Python 2 and 3 Works with local and online pdfs Getting Started Grab a copy of pdfx with easy_install or pip and run it:</description></item></channel></rss>