<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TypeScript on Chris Hager</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/tags/typescript/</link><description>Recent content in TypeScript on Chris Hager</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.metachris.com/tags/typescript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Starting a TypeScript Project in 2021</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/2021/04/starting-a-typescript-project-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/2021/04/starting-a-typescript-project-in-2021/</guid><description>This is a guide for starting a TypeScript project in 2021, using modern tooling:
TypeScript 4 Optionally esbuild - to bundle for browsers and Node.js Linting with typescript-eslint (tslint is deprecated) Testing with Jest (and ts-jest) Publishing to npm Continuous integration (GitHub Actions / GitLab CI) Automatic API documentation with TypeDoc You can clone the example repository, or follow the manual steps outlined in this post.
git clone https://github.</description></item><item><title>MicroPython-Ctl - a TypeScript library for talking to MicroPython devices</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/2021/01/micropython-ctl-a-typescript-library-for-talking-to-micropython-devices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/2021/01/micropython-ctl-a-typescript-library-for-talking-to-micropython-devices/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m happy to introduce MicroPython-Ctl: a TypeScript library for talking to MicroPython devices (such as ESP32/8266, Raspberry Pi Pico, Pyboard, WiPy, and many more).
Use micropython-ctl to quickly build apps that interact with MicroPython devices: Websites / webapps, Node.js programs, Electron applications, Visual Studio Code extensions, Mobile apps (eg. with React Native) and more.
Connect to devices over serial or network interface Run Python scripts, receive the output Manipulate files and directories Terminal (REPL) interaction mctl command-line utility Mount MicroPython devices locally (with FUSE, experimental) Typed and fully async (you can use await with any command).</description></item><item><title>Custom Errors in TypeScript 2.1</title><link>https://www.metachris.com/2017/01/custom-errors-in-typescript-2.1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.metachris.com/2017/01/custom-errors-in-typescript-2.1/</guid><description>TypeScript 2.1 introduced a number of breaking changes, among them that &amp;ldquo;Extending built-ins like Error, Array, and Map may no longer work&amp;rdquo;.
For a subclass like the following:
class FooError extends Error { constructor(m: string) { super(m); } sayHello() { return &amp;#34;hello &amp;#34; + this.message; } } methods may be undefined on objects returned by constructing these subclasses, so calling sayHello will result in an error. instanceof will be broken between instances of the subclass and their instances, so (new FooError()) instanceof FooError will return false.</description></item></channel></rss>